https://www.isa.org/about-isa/privacy-statement

Cookie Consent
This site uses cookies to store information on your computer.
Without consent certain enhanced features will not be available and future visits may require repeated consent, so it is recommended to accept the use of cookies.
Visit the ISA Privacy Policy for more information.
About ISA
Privacy Statement
Privacy Statement
In providing service to you, ISA and affiliated organizations must collect certain information, such as your address, phone number, fax number, email address, and other contact, profile, and billing information. We collect this kind of information only by voluntary disclosure directly from you. This type of personal information may be requested on a variety of transactional forms, including our membership application, product order forms, and event registrations. These forms may be either traditional paper-based forms in catalogs, brochures, or flyers or electronic based forms on our Web site or at events. The information we collect is intended to allow us to process your transaction and better serve you.
To help you understand how we use your personal information, we have developed a privacy policy. Our privacy policy is based on these principles:
We will disclose how we use the information we collect;
We will give you an opportunity to restrict our use of the information;
We will give you an opportunity to tell us not to give the information to others;
We will use commercially reasonable means to minimize the risk of unauthorized disclosures;
We will use commercially reasonable means to maintain the information accurately;
We will give you an opportunity to correct erroneous information in our records;
We will have the right to request personal identification information be removed from our system.
These principles and our policy apply whether we collect the information by paper or electronic form.
How we use your Personal Information
Web Site Specific Issues
IP Addresses
Cookies
E-mail Lists
Links
Limits on Use of Collected Information
Change/Modify your Information
How we use your Personal Information
Our ability to deliver the products and services of ISA relies on members and customers (supporters) to give us contact information (like your address, phone number, and email address) as well as demographic and profile information (like your zip code, age, industry, and areas of interest). We collect limited financial information, such as a check or credit card number, as required. We use this personal information primarily to provide services and targeted offerings. These services may involve periodically mailing our supporters communications, as well as catalogs and promotions of products and services we offer, including related information. One such service, an online membership directory, is available to ISA Members. From time to time, we will authorize companies, who we feel have something of value and relevance, to our supporters to receive and use this personal information. Financial information is used solely for payment of services requested. The collected demographic and profile data is used to tailor content and promotional information based on the supporters known or anticipated interests.
Supporter financial information will be transmitted as necessary and required to banks and credit card or other financial transaction processer for the processing of such payments to our accounts. Financial information will be maintained by us and the banks, credit card, or other financial transaction processer as necessary and required for the processing of transactions and for auditing, legal, or other similar business purposes. Such financial information will not be transmitted to unrelated third parties and will be encrypted as applicable.
-top-
Web Site Specific Issues
IP Addresses - The ISA and affiliated organization web sites automatically record in a log file the internet address of the computer accessing the site as well as the time and date of the access. This information does not personally identify you or contain your name or e-mail address. We use information from this log to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site.
ISA also utilizes a variety of tools which record activities on its web sites. This information is used to improve the user experience, and includes no personal identifying information.
-top-
Cookies
Our sites use "cookies" on a limited basis to provide and enhance various functionality and enable product purchases to be added to the cart.
Web browsers control access to store cookies (small text files) on your computer. Cookies are not programs and are not known to be damaging to your computer. Most browsers have an optional setting to deny cookies. If you disable cookies you may have problems accessing content, making purchases or leveraging other functionality of the ISA site.
Most web browsers provide a “Settings” or “Tools” tab to control cookies. Please refer to your specific browser documentation to locate and control this browser feature.
-top-
E-mail Lists
If you voluntarily disclose personal information to an e-mail list, user forum, or other messaging system on the ISA Web site, that information is available to anyone who can access that area. We cannot control what others may do with this information. You should refrain from disclosing anything you do not want publicly known in such areas.
-top-
Links
This site contains links to other Web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. If you happen to find an invalid or inappropriate link on any ISA web site please report it to info@isa.org.
-top-
Limits on Use of Collected Information
We provide members and customers the opportunity to restrict the use of the personal information collected. Members and customers may choose to restrict use by us to others. Members and customers may also elect for us not to use their e-mail address for communications.
To request a limit on the use of your information, contact us by:
By visiting the “My ISA” section of the ISA web site and reviewing your opt-out settings.
Postal mail to: ISA Data Protection Officer, 67 Alexander Drive, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27709 USA
Telephone: +1 919-549-8411
Fax: +1 919-549-8288
E-mail to: privacy@isa.org
If you make this choice, the information will be marked as restricted and, depending on the choice, you may not receive future communications from us.
We also may share personal data with several other parties. These include:
Sponsors of ISA activities;
Exhibitors at ISA events;
Publishers of ISA publications;
ISA Cloud service providers;
ISA Service providers who perform functions such as marketing, research, shipping and fulfilment; and
Vendors, such as ISA insurance and ISA credit card companies.
We also may share personal data in the event of a merger or asset sale/purchase transaction, and as required by law.
-top-
Change/Modify
Members and customers may change or correct information previously provided by editing their own record online or by contacting us as described above.
To edit the record online, log in to the ISA website. Click on My ISA Account and choose Phone and Email. Under Email, click on “Opt-in and Opt-out to ISA Emails” and designate your preferencess.
-top-
Questions
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with us, you can contact us using one of the above methods.
We reserve the right to modify our privacy policies and practices at any time without notice. This statement does not and is not intended to create any contractual or other legal rights. The policies in this statement continue in effect as of the last review on 1 May 2018.
-top-
Additional Provisions
Legal Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
There are several legal bases for the ISA’s collection and processing of personal data:
For the legitimate interests of ISA (including membership administration, delivery of products and services, communication of ISA offerings, direct marketing, and member and customer data analysis);
To perform a contract;
Based on consent; and
Legal compliance.
-top-
Site of Processing of Personal Data
Personal data of individuals collected by ISA may be stored and processed in the United States, Europe, or any other country in which ISA, its vendors, or partners maintain facilities. ISA generally collects and processes personal data in the US. In the event personal data is collected in the EU and is then transferred to the US, or is transferred to any other country outside of the EU, ISA will do so because there is a legal reason, such as in order to perform a contract, or to achieve a legitimate interest of ISA.
-top-
Data Retention
Personal data may be retained by ISA for so long as necessary or useful to pursue the legitimate interests of ISA. Other factors may include: the duration of the business or contractual relationship between ISA and an individual; archiving of historical information; and legal requirements, including limitations periods during which a legal claim might be brought.
-top-
Safeguards
ISA has put in place reasonable technical, physical, and administrative safeguards to protect personal data collected by ISA.
-top-
